[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b902", "question": "What color are many casinos decorated in to make patrons less aware of passing time?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bd", "question": "What is the longest word that can be spelled using only the letters in the top row of a QWERTY keyboard?", "answer": "Typewriter, peppertree, perpetuity, prerequire, proprietor, repertoire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600395b157a0e35c43f83895", "question": "What prompted Pablo Picasso's famous Blue Period?", "answer": "This period was an artistic response to his depression over the death of Carlos Casagemas,\u00a0a friend who shot himself.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8aacb01dd7bf43be5e761", "question": "What is the official German name of the Swiss Federal Railways?", "answer": "Schweizerische Bundesbahnen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c487", "question": "What is the common name for the infection known as \"tinea pedis\"?", "answer": "Athlete's foot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c257", "question": "In the computer world, what does the abbreviation RAM stand for?", "answer": "Random Access Memory", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab51", "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Slovenia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe937f36bd93ce3a4e5f67c", "question": "Hemophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Blood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3c", "question": "What 2003 Samuel L. Jackson/Colin Farrell movie was based on a mid-1970's  TV show?", "answer": "S.W.A.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5664733a95c66dc4fe761", "question": "In which film did Orson Welles play the role of Harry Lime?", "answer": "The Third Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddbfe6ce05a3942286d96", "question": "Which classic Christmas film premiered in theaters during the summer?", "answer": "\"Miracle on 34th Street\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e986bebfabb9c85d8a96b", "question": "Who released the album \"Tuesday Night Music Club\" in 1993?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cda7bb53d1af658864eb", "question": "What is Santa\u2019s postal code in Canada?", "answer": "H0H 0H0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5b", "question": "What literary work inspired Dream Theater's \"Pull Me Under\" song?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a5", "question": "What nation was led by Peter the Great?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a962", "question": "How many territories does the US administer over?", "answer": "16", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a427", "question": "In what country would you find Mount Everest?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd7", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"R\"?", "answer": "Romeo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3fa7ff048f679a45ab61", "question": "How many stomachs does a llama have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5e916ce05a3942286e36", "question": "In \"Pretty Woman\", what are the names of the salesgirls who help Vivian with her shopping spree?", "answer": "Mary Kate and Mary Frances", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f5", "question": "Where are you if you land at Norman Manley airport?", "answer": "Kingston Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed3", "question": "In what 1952 play is Giles Corey \"pressed\" to death, his last words being \"More weight\"?", "answer": "The Crucible", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f6", "question": "What age followed the Bronze Age?", "answer": "The Iron Age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f16745f7c52aae91cc07b7", "question": "In which continent would you find the Republic of Guinea-Bissau?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f858fe83fe1f2a824c2c", "question": "Under whose presidency were the waters in the fountains of the White House first dyed green in honor of Saint Patrick's Day?", "answer": "Barack Obama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f21201dd7bf43be5e80b", "question": "What food item do people often wear around their necks at beer festivals?", "answer": "Pretzels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f63301dd7bf43be5e830", "question": "What is the traditional gift for a 40th wedding anniversary?", "answer": "Ruby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d2e92596a59cbdfbd395", "question": "In which U.S. National Park is the colorful Grand Prismatic Spring?", "answer": "Yellowstone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cd4c877e98cb97778a34", "question": "What was the first country to declare internet a legal right?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7a", "question": "The BBC once banned The Beatles' \"Come Together\" for \"advertising\" what product in the lyrics?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad10", "question": "What city was talk show host Jerry Springer mayor of from 1977-1978?", "answer": "Cincinnati", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b2", "question": "Who wrote the 1924 novel \"Beau Geste\"?", "answer": "P. C. Wren", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523d0b736d4be723796b3d", "question": "What is the name of the robotic arm used on some of NASA\u2019s Space Shuttle flights?", "answer": "Canadarm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8adee01dd7bf43be5e780", "question": "What is the only king in a traditional deck of cards without a moustache?", "answer": "King of hearts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf0", "question": "What is the condition resulting from prolonged muscular or mental activity?", "answer": "Fatigue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab99bb621a8909e5c332d2e", "question": "What novel was the 1988 film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Who Censored Roger Rabbit?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6c", "question": "What is Ohio Stadium also known as?", "answer": "The Horseshoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69dda20565ad31a57c77e", "question": "What is the largest surviving Roman triumphal arch in the world?", "answer": "Arch of Constantine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f31301dd7bf43be5e814", "question": "What does AFLAC stand for in the US?", "answer": "American Family Life Assurance Company of Columbus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76b93eec85e375820b2c4", "question": "Where can you hike Hadrian\u2019s wall?", "answer": "England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe3ed658b5801b8f54a7fb1", "question": "From 1960 to 1965, which African country was a major area of Chinese political influence?", "answer": "Central African Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c7", "question": "Which Disney film features the ballad \"Can You Feel the Love Tonight\"?", "answer": "The Lion King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339645", "question": "Where did Kevin's parents go for Christmas in the 1990 movie \"Home Alone\"?", "answer": "France", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6e97a9e54d890926f6c7", "question": "Just off the coast of Venezuela, one will find Aruba, Bonaire, and Cura\u00e7ao, collectively known as what?", "answer": "The three islands are collectively known as the ABC Islands, or Dutch Antilles.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c1bc4f032c0db195b478", "question": "What tribe of Native Americans was the first to encounter the Pilgrims?", "answer": "The Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea43f3ff048f679a45ab8b", "question": "What is the name of the submerged fringe of a continent?", "answer": "Continental Shelf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada0", "question": "Who was better known as \"Sundance Kid\"?", "answer": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f3eeaaf848b908361b86a", "question": "What country's flag features a trident?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933c", "question": "Who was JR Ewing's brother on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Bobby Ewing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2e", "question": "What company bought naming rights to the Florida Suncoast Dome in 1996?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ee3208d98002fdd633d2", "question": "What is the literal meaning of the Dutch word \"brandewijn\"?", "answer": "Burned wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f9f4c14af848b908361b87e", "question": "What was Google\u2019s original name?", "answer": "BackRub", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029fb8cad1ec93f27df763", "question": "Who was Strongbow cider named after?", "answer": "Richard de Clare", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f975fe83fe1f2a824c33", "question": "What does the final day of Passover celebrate?", "answer": "The arrival of the Israelites to the Red Sea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a73690aac110e4167084", "question": "What customary vessel is used for consuming yerba mate?", "answer": "A gourd", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c4", "question": "In the sitcom, \"Only Fools and Horses\" what is Rodney's middle name?", "answer": "Charlton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a324", "question": "What was the full name of Mangum P.I.?", "answer": "Thomas Magnum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b26", "question": "In \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\", which dwarf's job is it to check the authenticity of the gems they mine?", "answer": "Doc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59decf2fea2747c8aff16d1b", "question": "What is sometimes referred to as Zulu time?", "answer": "Greenwich Mean Time", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5eb", "question": "What type of garment are \"Elephant bells\"?", "answer": "Pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66c5852a821ff76ae8b11", "question": "During which year was cocaine removed as an ingredient in Coca Cola?", "answer": "1903", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51c1aff04d658268c9314", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eb0c7f83302ff91e4649f", "question": "What year was the luxury brand \"Tiffany & Co.\" founded?", "answer": "1837", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067c00ff9c0647b50a8069", "question": "What artist received the most Grammy Awards in 2016?", "answer": "Kendrick Lamar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339167", "question": "What is Mickey Mouse's dog's name?", "answer": "Pluto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab959c86faa38a764be517", "question": "Before starting to produce cars in the late 1940s, what did SAAB originally manufacture?", "answer": "Aircrafts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc11c0469bb8041d07a079", "question": "What is the name of a popular Italian orange and vanilla flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Tuaca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7880ff048f679a45abda", "question": "What do antioxidants neutralize?", "answer": "Free radicals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f31aff048f679a45aabd", "question": "What is the most volcanically active body in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter's moon Io", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b13", "question": "Who did Lionel Richie duet with on the 1981 #1 smash \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c88e67122f44c2d77a29c41", "question": "Why did people go to Sutter's Mill, California, from 1848 to the mid 1850's?", "answer": "Gold was discovered there", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae1", "question": "In what country was the International Red Cross founded?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded2caea2747c8aff16d42", "question": "What line on a weather map links all points of equal pressure?", "answer": "Isobar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf25", "question": "What does a linguist study?", "answer": "Languages", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5900878d5304ceedb84e8998", "question": "The parents of which Rock and Roll superstar were called Vernon and Gladys?", "answer": "Elvis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049d61cf93664eb10486ad", "question": "Julia Louis-Dreyfus was born on Friday, January 13, of what year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb20f65ff7d326b622a70", "question": "What is the study of rocks and their formation called?", "answer": "Petrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980d", "question": "What pop star's first and middle names are Katherine Dawn?", "answer": "KD Lang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c3", "question": "On what island was Napoleon born?", "answer": "Corsica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe657daae7e414034b5aee3", "question": "In the Book of Deuteronomy, which mountain is also known as the Mount of Blessing?", "answer": "Mount Gerizim", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a142", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Gasoline Alley\"?", "answer": "Rod Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339412", "question": "On the \"Abbey Road\" album cover, which member of the Beatles is on the far left?", "answer": "George Harrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e8063dde59ea584496feaf", "question": "What word is used as the international radio distress call?", "answer": "Mayday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cd40d8c685cf15b733e9893", "question": "In the Simpsons what is the discount on the chocolate in the \"Land of Chocolate\"?", "answer": "Half Price", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339289", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", who fights with a bow and arrow besides Katness?", "answer": "Glimmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cec", "question": "What Beatles song is set \"somewhere in the Black Mountain hills of Dakota\"?", "answer": "Rocky Raccoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339696", "question": "What is Cartman's first name on the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Eric", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339556", "question": "For what film did Liza Minnelli win the Academy Award for Best Leading Actress?", "answer": "Cabaret", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e47", "question": "What dog is the hero of Jack London's \"The Call of the Wild\"?", "answer": "Buck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde7", "question": "What sport has thirteen players per team in \"league\" rules but fifteen in \"union\" play?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe528091bf59ab7d2e380fc", "question": "Before it was called the Big Mac, McDonald's signature sandwich went by what name?", "answer": "The Aristocrat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8d", "question": "In what year did Babe Ruth reach 500 career home runs?", "answer": "1929", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b27", "question": "Who is credited with writing the first detective story, \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef59a56ce05a3942286e05", "question": "Walnut Grove, Minnesota is the setting for which television series?", "answer": "\"Little House on the Prairie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77ce4924f0f7a362efd545", "question": "A-ha and Edward Grieg hail from what country ", "answer": "Norway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e90fb89d7247dfc0fa00306", "question": "From the anime \"Fairy Tail\" who is known to be Titania, The Queen of Fairies?", "answer": "Erza Scarlet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e53cfcbed638185eaa2c", "question": "Where can you drive on the Seven Mile Bridge?", "answer": "Florida Keys", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a552833e1c6f9840ba3197", "question": "The telephone country code 82 would connect you with which country?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2dc", "question": "What do ladybugs feed on during hibernation?", "answer": "Stored fat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a1a38012f2a7826b9b8727", "question": "Barbara Gordon is better know as what heroine?", "answer": "Batgirl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba582874c93a3298b2151", "question": "What name did George Costanza from the TV show \"Seinfeld\" want to name his first child?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd69", "question": "According to the 1940s jingle, after what two men pitched did Boston Braves fans \"pray for rain\"?", "answer": "Spahn and Sain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7b", "question": "Who has been called the first victim of the \"Madden curse\" due to his abrupt 1999 retirement?", "answer": "Barry Sanders", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7e54ff048f679a45ac0b", "question": "A BTU refers to what?", "answer": "The amount of energy required to raise one pound of water one degree Fahrenheit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93d576bd93ce3a4e5f6b4", "question": "What type of rock is formed by consolidation of molten magma?", "answer": "Igneous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339800", "question": "What label owns the rights to every Elvis recording ever made", "answer": "RCA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb357612627b8fe95581be3", "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state, Queensland?", "answer": "Brisbane", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008df78f4f3bc4a292f862b", "question": "The two men in the Old Testament who walked with God are?", "answer": "From Genesis 5:24 and 6:9, Enoch and Noah were two very faithful and pious patriarchs who walked with the Lord.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a4", "question": "What was the name of the high school in the TV show \"Our Miss Brooks\"?", "answer": "Madison High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef5", "question": "What 1984 Ratt hit featured a cross-dressing Milton Berle in its video?", "answer": "Round and Round", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a389", "question": "What country is Ibiza a part of?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e5", "question": "What popular Motown group was originally known as \"The Primettes\"?", "answer": "The Supremes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe769d3eec85e375820b2b2", "question": "Where was \"Cibik Ridge\" in World War II?", "answer": "Bougainville Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab72", "question": "What is the capital of Bangladesh?", "answer": "Dhaka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b5", "question": "What is 1 knot of speed equivalent to?", "answer": "1 Nautical Mile per Hour", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ae", "question": "Along with Karl Marx, who penned \"The Communist Manifesto\" in 1848?", "answer": "Friedrich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce2", "question": "At what US city did Bugs Bunny traditionally lament taking a left \"toin\"?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a5", "question": "What city is home for TV's Golden Girls?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5dd", "question": "What were barcodes first used for?", "answer": "To label railroad cars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523ecc736d4be723796b54", "question": "What three provinces requested a single Dominion be formed in 1867, thus beginning to shape modern Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and the Province of Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b6ece662d71a53651010", "question": "\"Lean Mean Thirteen\" was published in 2007 by which author?", "answer": "Janet Evanovich", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5eb73cea5e259d7869087332", "question": "A \"waltz-length\" dress stops at what part of the body?", "answer": "The calf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f6", "question": "What takes place in Happy Valley, Hong Kong?", "answer": "Horse racing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6003952057a0e35c43f83892", "question": "Any color plus black is called what?", "answer": "A shade", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f89", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Funny Girl\"?", "answer": "Barbra Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e16506d333868d34d727", "question": "Who wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\"?", "answer": "Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96acf23c87fd04dd15e15", "question": "As of 2020, who was the last person to go directly from Vice President to President of the United States?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a974661d1b4d384d5d682", "question": "What nationality is designer Karl Lagerfield?", "answer": "German", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e25", "question": "What 1904 play was subtitled \"The Boy Who Wouldn't Grow Up\"?", "answer": "Peter Pan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b0e93c964118b2bb3809cb", "question": "St. Dwynwen is the patron saint of lovers in which European country?", "answer": "Wales", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e70", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Jennifer Eight\"?", "answer": "Uma Thurman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71c", "question": "In what country does Santa typically sport a long coat and beard?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c2", "question": "Which artist married Carrie Fisher in 1983?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3b0eff048f679a45ab31", "question": "Who invented the microscope?", "answer": "Zacharias Janssen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eaee8f83302ff91e4648e", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"ad hoc\" literally mean?", "answer": "For this", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049e7ecf93664eb10486b4", "question": "What country does the rock band \"Enter Shikari\" originate from?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a446", "question": "What mountain overlooks Cape Town, South Africa?", "answer": "Table Mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa62a73838c5c8a417f2e", "question": "What is the fungi Hydnellum peckii, also known as?", "answer": "The bleeding tooth fungus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a645", "question": "Which US state is known as the \"Land of Lincoln\"?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c6f1877e98cb977789c5", "question": "Which East Asian country celebrates Golden Week?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3d", "question": "What did the Texan army shout during the Battle of San Jacinto?", "answer": "Remember the Alamo!", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab73", "question": "Dhaka is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339295", "question": "On what book series is the HBO TV series \"True Blood\" based?", "answer": "The Southern Vampire Mysteries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98d", "question": "What part of a piano's action permits the keys to be struck in quick repetition?", "answer": "Escapement", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55c", "question": "In what direction do most cyclones whirl in the Southern Hemisphere?", "answer": "Clockwise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f3", "question": "How many fingers does a boy scout extend in a salute?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a709", "question": "What is the third largest National Park in the US?", "answer": "Everglades National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0bf", "question": "What is the fear of progress known as?", "answer": "Prosophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccf", "question": "In which Hitchcock movie is the protagonist confined to a wheelchair?", "answer": "Rear Window", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d1855f3b17032616b590fd", "question": "What year was instant coffee was first patented in France?", "answer": "1881", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b3", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan became famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b7", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Uruguay and Venezuela?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c37bc815febcc896f9273", "question": "What is the tenth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Capricorn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69fbb20565ad31a57c78f", "question": "What US founding father also founded the University of Pennsylvania?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a552bb3e1c6f9840ba319c", "question": "Which Asian country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d1185a4fea7fe947a22284", "question": "By what name is Lignite often referred to as?", "answer": "Brown coal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d7", "question": "Which singer had a 1964 hit with \"King of the Road\"?", "answer": "Roger Miller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0f2ff048f679a45aaac", "question": "Wiccaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Witches and witchcraft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aaa", "question": "Who wrote the Christmas novel, The Lost Angel in 1971?", "answer": "Elizabeth Goudge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5922002ba4edfd43a087add7", "question": "A \"Panatela\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Cigar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b424", "question": "What year did Konrad Adenauer become the first Chancellor of West Germany?", "answer": "1949", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c112", "question": "What country was figure skater Elvis Stojko born in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ae", "question": "What is the capitol of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8d", "question": "In the \"Popeye\" comics, on what day would Wimpy gladly pay you for a hamburger?", "answer": "Tuesday", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c67c877e98cb977789ba", "question": "Where are the Mayan ruins of Tikal located?", "answer": "Guatemala", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062a19c9d816e292245c13", "question": "What Flemish Baroque painter is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces?", "answer": "Peter Paul Rubens -- He was a proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60136f851381754895396377", "question": "What superhero uses a device called \"The Cosmic Treadmill\"?", "answer": "Flash -- The Cosmic Treadmill is used to help the Flash amplify his already considerable powers.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdcd", "question": "What kind of tea takes its name from the Chinese for \"Black dragon\"?", "answer": "Oolong", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa3d86ce05a3942286eab", "question": "Whose hand is shown drawing the charcoal portrait of Kate Winslet in \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "James Cameron's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb1beeff497e33de8057919", "question": "How many points did LeBron James score in his very first NBA game?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c439877e98cb9777899c", "question": "What country is home to \"Snake Island\"?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9b", "question": "What is the family name of the creator of Tobasco sauce?", "answer": "McIllhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9cd", "question": "In which continent would you find the Mackenzie river?\u00a0", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76f", "question": "A \"brigantine\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Sailing ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4a4349076251badbeab2", "question": "What holiday commemorates the day the last slaves were freed in Texas?", "answer": "Juneteenth -- It commemorates the day (June 19, 1865) that slaves in Galveston, Texas learned that they were free.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339040", "question": "Who wrote a book entitled \"The Adventures of Lord Iffy Boatrace\"?", "answer": "Bruce Dickinson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926a", "question": "What movie follows the ins and outs of Lester Burnham's mid-life crisis?", "answer": "American Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ef6406d333868d34d778", "question": "What kind of grass has been used at Wimbledon since 2002?", "answer": "Ryegrass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62b", "question": "What is the brightest star in the night sky?", "answer": "Sirius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb09", "question": "What do pumpkins grow on?", "answer": "Vines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad71", "question": "Who was nominated as the Democratic Party's presidential candidate for the 1968 US election?", "answer": "Hubert Humphrey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b361", "question": "Which planet was discovered in 1846?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c1", "question": "The viceroy butterfly is so named because of its mimicry of what other species?", "answer": "The monarch butterfly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394af", "question": "What was the name of the high school in which the TV show \"Room 222\" took place?", "answer": "Walt Whitman High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d2", "question": "In the TV show \"Knight Rider\", what does K.I.T.T.'s name stand for?", "answer": "Knight Industries Two Thousand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b310", "question": "Sun Yat-sen is considered the founding father of what country?", "answer": "Taiwan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c13b877e98cb97778976", "question": "Which two US states are connected by the Natchez\u2013Vidalia Bridge?", "answer": "Mississippi and Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19c", "question": "What dog breed was the official 1972 Summer Olympics mascot?", "answer": "Dachshund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53c", "question": "What word in the English language with three consecutive sets of double letters?", "answer": "Bookkeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600397f857a0e35c43f83899", "question": "What term did the artist Kurt Schwitters invent to describe his works made from scavenged fragments and objects?", "answer": "Father of installation art and a pioneer in fusing collage and abstraction, invented the term\u00a0Merz from the German word\u00a0Kommerz.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339325", "question": "In the movie \"Monsters Inc.\", what are the monsters most scared of?", "answer": "Children", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f6", "question": "What garden vegetable was known for years as green Italian squash?", "answer": "Zucchini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ec49fe83fe1f2a824bfe", "question": "In the United States, 1 May is officially recognized as Loyalty Day. Which American President instituted this holiday?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a988", "question": "What city named its airport after John Foster Dulles?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3a", "question": "In the song \"Zip-a-Dee-Doo-Dah\", what kind of animal sits on Uncle Remus' shoulder?", "answer": "A bluebird", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb8", "question": "What name did photographer Emmanuel Rudnitsky assume?", "answer": "Man Ray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59220151a4edfd43a087adda", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Dreams From My Father\"?", "answer": "Barack Obama's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a720", "question": "Which city is home to the South-of-Market district?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fed2bc4ec223966ae8f8912", "question": "What did Tommy say after killing Stacks in \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "\"Make that coffee to go.\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc23eec223966ae8f8873", "question": "Razzie awards are meant to go to bad movies, but who got nominated for directing the now widely respected film Scarface?", "answer": "Brian De Palma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9323574a5ce6b56b8236", "question": "Who was the Roman goddess of youth?", "answer": "Juventas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a44", "question": "What dance craze inspired the 1990 film \"The Forbidden Dance\"?", "answer": "The lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec4", "question": "What play did Agatha Christie write as an eightieth birthday present for Queen Elizabeth's grandmother?", "answer": "The Mousetrap", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339992", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Cosby Show\" were made?", "answer": "197", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba74", "question": "What NHL team won the Stanley Cup six times during the 1970\u2019s?", "answer": "Montreal Canadiens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfdfd9dc5ec6cd98a8327", "question": "Which of Shakespeare's plays features a sorcerer named Prospero?", "answer": "\"The Tempest\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b641", "question": "What gas makes up approximately 74 percent of the Sun's mass?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d0", "question": "Which was the first ocean to be crossed by ship and by plane?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72cce8d0874f1a5e2d1c25", "question": "What is a \"Winkle Picker\" or \"Winklepicker\"?", "answer": "An English long pointed shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbaea1a0738315b1fb74e2a", "question": "Phlebitis is the inflimation of what?", "answer": "A vein", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b117", "question": "In American history, what 20th century decade is often described as \"Roaring\"?", "answer": "1920's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b2", "question": "The hottest natural chemical according to the Scoville Scale, resiniferatoxin, comes from what plant?", "answer": "Resin spurge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ec22f68dc25ca9e12ef62b", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a5", "question": "Who played Carrie in the movie of the same name in 1976?", "answer": "Sissy Spacek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b2420565ad31a57c75c", "question": "Which World War II battle saw the greatest number of tanks used in world history?", "answer": "The Battle of Kursk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdda", "question": "Ash Wednesday marks the first day of what?", "answer": "Lent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70bfcf96e155acab35d27", "question": "What is Chiroptophobia?", "answer": "Fear of Bats", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b42e", "question": "How old was Alfred Hitchcock when he died?", "answer": "80", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d971908b8581f80b092a8", "question": "What country was host to the \u201c2017 World Expo\u201d?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0d", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Crazy Craving?", "answer": "Honeycomb", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e43", "question": "On what island is the TV series \"Wings\" set?", "answer": "Nantucket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a1", "question": "What is the literal translation of the condition known as \"diprosopus\"?", "answer": "Two-faced", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebe", "question": "What badge number was retired by the LAPD when Jack \"Joe Friday\" Webb died in 1982?", "answer": "714", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e414fe83fe1f2a824bad", "question": "What was Monte Cassino?", "answer": "A large monastery in central Italy where the Germans defended Rome from Allied forces", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cfcfbb53d1af658864f6", "question": "What is the curved part of the candy cane known as?", "answer": "The warble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11a", "question": "What is the real identity of Aquaman?", "answer": "Arthur Curry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e44", "question": "What American TV actor plays himself as a fallen angel in Wim Wenders' \"Wings of Desire\"?", "answer": "Peter Falk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002444a4be4723ccac221a1", "question": "What is the only work of art Michelangelo ever signed?", "answer": "The\u00a0\"Piet\u00e0,\" a masterpiece depicting the body of Jesus on his mother's lap, is the only work of any sort that he ever signed.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2c", "question": "Created by Al Capp, what comic strip appeared in newspapers from 1934 until 1977?", "answer": "Li'l Abner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13d", "question": "In 1906, who became the first American to win the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Teddy Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac8", "question": "The folklore characters known as \"oni\" originated in which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c919", "question": "What type of number has no factors other than 1 and itself?", "answer": "Prime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73602eec85e375820b257", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894d", "question": "What William Golding novel tells the story of a group of boys cast away on a desert island?", "answer": "Lord of the Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb666b5dad637d903c8836", "question": "Which English city was Alfred the Great's capital city?", "answer": "Winchester", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef96c96ce05a3942286ea1", "question": "Which martial art does Miss Piggy practice?", "answer": "Karate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2150731a458464a93c45c", "question": "What does a fendersmith do?", "answer": "Maintains fireplaces", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e147a756ca6dac04a20ca4f", "question": "When did Thomas Jefferson purchase the territory of Louisiana?", "answer": "1803", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940b", "question": "What is the name of Drew Barrymore's character in the 1982 movie E.T. the Extra Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Gertie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec26ac8dc25ca9e12ef64e", "question": "What is a male goose called?", "answer": "Gander", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cde", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured John Travolta and Forest Whitaker?", "answer": "Battlefield Earth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636c06967692ea851899a7", "question": "How many years after the 1990\u2019s movie \"Independence Day\", was sequel \"Independence Day: Resurgence\" released?", "answer": "20 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b918364247bf200fb888", "question": "What is the fear of flutes called?", "answer": "Aulophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81d", "question": "What year was the lava lamp launched?", "answer": "1965", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e0d2fe83fe1f2a824b92", "question": "Against which country did the Soviet Union instigate an armed conflict in late 1939?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a1", "question": "What US state is called the \"Centennial State\"?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523d89736d4be723796b44", "question": "For what period of time is the Governor General of Canada appointed?", "answer": "Unfixed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e4", "question": "When was the Halley's Comet periodicity discovered?", "answer": "1705", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb5fb05dad637d903c8827", "question": "The Vatican owns a telescope in what U.S. state?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a0", "question": "How many gallons does a tun barrel typically hold?", "answer": "252", "category": "general"}]